### **Spiros Xiarchos**

Network Engineer

Email: sp@xiarchos.gr Web: sp.xiarchos.gr

#### About Me

Hey there, I'm Spiros and I am an undergraduate student in the Department of Informatics of the Ionian University.

My interests include, but are not limited to, gaining experience in the following areas:

- Networking (Firewalling, SDWAN)
- Web development (e.g. React or Angular)
- E-shop Frameworks (e.g. WooCommerce or Magento)
- Mobile development (iOS only)
- End-to-end testing suites (e.g. puppeteer)

Technical skills are not the only area I have developed through my expirience. My peers describe me as a valuable team member, who knows how to work under strict deadlines and provide quality results.

#### Education

Specialization in Information Systems.

Main courses follow:

B.Sc. Informatics
Ionian University, Corfu GR

10/2015 - 09/23 (Thesis Pending) Analysis and Design of Information Systems.

Strategic Management of Information Systems Software,
Application, Communications and Network Security.

Information System Security Management Information
Privacy Enhancing Policies and Techonolgies
Social and Legal Issues of ICTs

### Experience

Website/Email Hosting.

## IT & Network Consultant

Freelance, Athens GR

06/2021 - Present

App Development (Custumisation and Deployment of Open Source Applications).

Azure, Office 365, Active Directory Services, MS
Exchange, VMware and Proxmox Administration • Network
Design, Implementation and Support.
Fileserver and Remote Backup Solutions.

#### **Network Engineer**

Marpoint Ltd, Marousi GR

06/2022 - 05/2023

Configuration and Maintenance of Networking Eqipment (Routers/Switches/Access Points/4G-5G Antennas) (Mikrotik).

Network Architecture and Installation.

Network and ICT Support.

Server and NAS Configuration, Installation, Maintenance and Troobleshouting (Proxmox / Windows Serveer / Synology).

Creation of detailed technical documentation for project implementations and integrations.

Intercompass MPD, Glyfada GR

06/2022 - 05/2023

Network Administrator Network Design, Deployment and Administration (Mikrotik/Cisco).

**System Operations Assitant** 

(WHM CPanel/Direct Admin/Microsoft 365/Proxmox/ Synology).

Comprehensive project documentation deployment.

#### **Network Management Customer Support**

NET7, Corfu GR 06/2022 - 05/2023 WISP Network Manager (Ubiquiti/Mikrotik). Customer Support Manager (UISP CRM).

# Network Management IT Support

Messinian Networks, Kalamata GR 06/2016 - 11/2022

21/06/2021 - 30/11/2022: Network Management and Customer Support Service (Kalamata). (UISP CRM/NMS)
01/09/2016 - 20/06/2021: B2B IT Support and Network Management (Corfu). (Mikrotik/Synology/VMware)
23/06/2016 - 31/08/2016: Training on Network Installations and IT Support (Kalamata). (Mikrotik/Ubiquiti)

#### A Little More About Me

Apart from my job's related interests I'm keen on:

- Traveling
- Audiophilism and Vinyl Records
- MotoGP